José Enciso

Junior Software Developer - HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, MongoDB, SQL.

CONTACT

Birstall, Leicester +44 775 270 1658 josejefloen@gmail.com <u>linkedin.com/in/joseenciso-88/</u> github.com/joseenciso

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Jquery
- Bootstrap 4 & 5

- Python
- Flask, Django
- AWS S3
- Stripe
- Problem solver
- Git and GitHub

AWARDS

Software Development Diploma

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native) English

German, level A1

SUMMARY

I am passionate about technology, hardware and software with 5 years experience in the electronic engineering industry as a qualified electronic technician. I have always been very curious about how things work and they are being made, reasons that solidified my choice to educate myself through a bootcamp with Code Institute and become a software engineer and chase a new career.

PROJECTS

Abel Pineda Consultant — Consultant Website

Currently working on this static single page website for a friend to help him to boost his project as a restaurant and pub's consultant to keep my knowledge as fresh as possible and challenging myself to learn more. The technologies to be used for this project are HTML, CSS, Javascript and jQuery on the frontend, for the backend still deciding whether it is needed or not.

https://github.com/joseenciso/abelpineda/ https://joseenciso.github.io/abelpineda/

EDUCATION

Code Institute, Online — Software Developer

January 2019 - April 2021

Course credit-rated by Edinburgh Napier university broken into 4 milestones projects, where I learnt the frontend technologies such as HTML, CSS, Javascript and the usages the frameworks like bootstrap and jquery till the backend with Python and Flask and Django as web frameworks, databases as SQL and MongoDB, deploying two of the milestones projects on Heroku, uses of control version with Git, GitHub and the AWS S3 service to store images.

• **Backpocket** — *eCommerce*

FullStack eCommerce project hosted in Heroku that works with the language python and the web framework dJango in the back-end, and for the front-end Bootstrap 5, HTML and CSS.

This project deployed in Heroku, the images are stored in Amazon AWS S3 and also integrates Stripe for online payments.

https://backpocket-store.herokuapp.com/

https://github.com/joseenciso/Backpocket

• Bottleneck — Video Games blog

FullStack project deployed in Heroku that works with Python's web framework Flask in the BackEnd, MongoDB as a database connected to AtlasDB to store images and text, and in the FrontEnd the technologies are HTML, CSS and Bootstrap 4.

https://bottleneck-gaming.herokuapp.com/

https://github.com/joseenciso/bottleneck

• **Live Band**— Artist's show finder

This project is focused on using Javascript and JQuery to retrieve data from an external Rest-API and presenting them into a user interface.

https://joseenciso.github.io/Live-Band/

https://github.com/joseenciso/Live-Band

• **Jose Enciso**— Portfolio website

This is my very first project, this project is intended to change as I am getting experience with the technologies and the trends, adding little by little a better UI/UX, better HTML, CSS and Javascript implementation and adding Backend functionalities in the near future.

https://joseenciso.github.io/Jose-Enciso/

https://github.com/joseenciso/Jose-Enciso

Code Institute, Mexico — Software Development

January 2018 - March 2021

I started the first year of Software Development and had to leave the career for some difficulties back in that time.

Open University of Mexico, Mexico — Software Development

Unconclude

I started the first year of Software Development and had to leave the career for some difficulties back in that time.

EXPERIENCE

${\bf Hammonds\ Furniture,\ Hinkley-\it Operator}$

Sept 2018 - May 2021

Pizza Hut, Leicester — Foodie

Dec 2014 - Oct 2019

Sanmina-SCI, Guadalajara-México— Electronic Technician

Oct 2012 - Mar 2014